plays plays with grit And at the
end of the day it's all about
will Like you've got to be
willing you know to go hunt as
as as I would like love to
say you know So a lot of great
things on on tape Um he's
growing as a backfield blocker
Um but again I just can't I
can't wait to get to work with
him. I say I I think of it that
he was a walk-on at Wisconsin
and then obviously transferred
to Indiana Why
do you think he was overlooked
early in his career Does that
just speak to his development
from then to where he is now?
Yeah No definitely I mean
there's there's so many athletes
that have had that type of path
you know have had to overcome
overcome adversity in their
careers Um this
is just you know the icing on
the cake for his story Um and
I'm sure that going through that
transition and going going
through varsity as a young man
you know put him in a position
now that where he's getting
drafted you know by the
Pittsburgh Steelers So uh I'm
excited to hear hear more about
his story but I'm sure it molded
him to the person that he is
today. There are some NFL teams
that treat the fullback as this
sort of forgotten vestage of the
past I'm assuming this means
that that's not going to be What
do you see the fullback as the
role in the sophom? Yeah Um I'd
say coach is a
smashmouth football guy you know
and And so um I would I would
envision that the role for the
fullback is you know to be
versatile you know to be able to
help the team
in multiple ways You know we're
talking talking offensively
right now but this is a four
core special teams
player that's going to be able
to have team value because of
you know what he brings to the
entire team And so ultimately
whether it's a fullback whether
it's a tight end you know
or a running back your job is to
find ways to bring value to the
team And so I definitely
envision us us utilizing the
position often Um and um you
know that's going to define
himself once he gets here and
we're able to see you know uh
where he fits us
us best and where he can grow.
Last year's fullback was also
the shortyard his quarterback
You envision that for him? Hey
I'm I'm following coach's lead
on that brother I'm I'm
following coach's lead Whatever
his vision is we'll roll with it
Great question. He started his
career as a linebacker in
college and then transitioned to
the offensive side of the ball
How can those those skills as a
linebacker be transferred to
what you envision his role? Oh
man that's a great question as
well Imagine a young man who's
playing the the offensive side
of the ball who has chemistry
and understanding on the
defensive side of the ball So
he's able to see it from their
perspective their eyes and use
use that to his strength Um and
so um it's worked out well for
him It's worked out great for
him right We're talking about
him and he's going to be here
soon Um I can definitely see him
using using that to to his
strengths and the best of his
ability Um and then um you know
in my
mind just the simple fact that
he played linebacker you can see
that dog that physicality style
of play that he brings And I'm
so excited that we get to work
with that on the offensive side
of the ball. How does he fit in
with the current tight ends on
the team Yeah you know I I I
really can't answer that
question I haven't done a lot of
you know spent a lot of time
evaluating our current tight
ends Um but again it goes back
to just um flexib flexib
flexibility availability um and
position flex You know I'm sure
he's going to find ways to help
out
multiple rooms not just uh our
room and the running back's room
a valuable asset to the tight
end tighting room as well.
Anyone else? Um as a coaching
staff do you guys kind of have
unique amount of insight into
Indiana this year with Frank
Frank um Adam Henry
being over there and all kind of
the Pittsburgh connections. Yeah
Um I I wouldn't say any more
insight than any other team You
know we did our due diligence as
far as studying the tape
throughout the year you know
spending time watch watching you
know and um you know um um games
in person um
film you know different guys
going out and seeing him at his
combine and things of that
nature but nothing nothing more
or less than you would with any
other players Just so so happens
that you know they played uh for
the championship in in in
college football and so you were
able to see him you know
participate and play a little
bit more than you would other
players who their seasons end
end a little bit sooner So
normal due diligence but uh man
super excited about Riley. Riley
transferred transferred in
became a team captain without
even spending more than one year
with the team How much did that
his character kind of draw you
guys to and where do you see
that team team captain? Yeah
character is everything You know
character is everything
especially making that
transition quickly within one
one year and earning that um for
the Indiana um you know but he's
got a fresh start You know he's
going to have to reestablish
himself Um I always tell the
players the first way to lead is
to lead by example And so um
definitely looking forward to
speaking to him and just talking
about the expectations and the
standards of our organization
and and program but he's going
to have to reestablish himself
and build the relationships with
with the locker room It's all
about the connection in the
locker room Um and hopefully we
gain those leadership qualities
that he's already established in
college hear about the third or
fourth coach who's come in here
and talked about position flex
with the new player How much is
that uh organization philosophy
for Mike McCarthy on on down?
Huge philosophy and the reason
why is because as a player on
this team you always always have
to be um
understanding that you have to
put the team first Everything's
about the team
Everything's about the
connection in the locker room
And so if players even even
coaches you know if we find ways
we we call it across the hall we
collaborate with other coaches
players collaborating with other
teammates and finding ways to
bring value to the team is is is
huge huge and is massive uh for
our success. He said he's not
any certain touchdown separation
or or anything like that How how
much do you value a guy that's
not like look at me as we're
way? Yeah I love it I mean
you're talking about the
fullback position right It's a a
almost like an extension of the
offensive line right They don't
get a ton of glory Um that you
know it's not a lot of shine
It's more or less doing my job
to the best of my ability so
that that I can serve the team
And so I love that about him Um
definitely going to talk to him
about that though because he
gets the opportunity to score he
needs to to celebrate right Um
you celebrate Uh it's so hard to
score in the National Football
League and just that would be a
special moment for his family uh
for his loved ones and of course
for the the organization So
we'll we'll talk about that
We'll get some going. All right
Thanks coach. Thank you
you you